Preliminary Inventory to the Frank Barbaro Papers WAG.121
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Frank Barbaro Papers
1977-1996
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Barbaro, Frank, 1927-
WAG.121
16 Linear Feet (16 boxes)
Frank Barbaro was born in Brooklyn in 1927. A leftist and former longshoreman, he was elected to the New York State Assembly in 1972 and served for 26 years. As chairman of the Labor Committee, Barbaro was dedicated to advancing workers' protection laws. After leaving the Assembly, he served on the New York State Supreme Court for six years. This unprocessed collection consists mostly of correspondence and hearing transcripts from Frank Barbaro's service in the New York State Assembly (1976-1996). There is also material on specific legislation and events, nearly all of it labor related.
Scope and Contents
This unprocessed collection consists mostly of correspondence and hearing transcripts from Frank Barbaro's service in the New York State Assembly (1976-1996). There is also material on specific legislation and events, nearly all of it labor related.
Historical/Biographical Note
Frank Barbaro was born in Brooklyn in 1927. A leftist and former longshoreman, he was elected to the New York State Assembly in 1972 and served for 26 years. As chairman of the Labor Committee, Barbaro was dedicated to advancing workers' protection laws. After leaving the Assembly, he served on the New York State Supreme Court for six years.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Frank Barbaro, 1997. The accession number associated with this gift is 1997.053.
Labor laws and legislation -- New York (State); New York (State) -- Politics and government.; Barbaro, Frank, 1927-; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly
- Inventory
  - Whistleblower bill, 1991-92; Unemployment Insurance, Financing, 1993; Unemployment Insurance, Correspondence, 1986-90, 1993-94; Union-busting, 1982-92; Phelps Dodge Strike, 1985-86; Stony Brook grad students, 1990-91; Eden Park, 1979-86; Strike busting 1989-91; Bills and hearings, legislation 1993; Watertown, N.Y. strike 1990-93; Workers Compensation 1988-1987; Memorandum and legislation 1982-92; Union correspondence 1990-92, 1979-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1993 (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence 1977, 1983-1992; V.D.T. 1977 (Box 3)
  - Memorandum, 1983; Livery Drivers, 1991-93; Workers compensation, 1993; Taxi and Limo commission Regulations 1993; Meeks Bell, 1993; Messenger Service Bill, 1994; General Correspondence, 1992-93, 1983-1994 (Box 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1985-1990; Prison Labor Hearings, 1992; Corporate Decency Act, 1989; El Salvador Report, 1990, 1985-1992 (Box 6)
  - Public Hearings and Transcript, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Public Hearings 1986-90; General Correspondence 1991, 1986, 1993; Assembly records 1981-84, 1990-91, 1981-1993 (Box 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1988-93; Assembly records, 1976-82; Child Labor Law Bill, 1990, 1976-1993 (Box 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 10)
  - Public Hearings, 1992-93; General Correspondence, 1989-92, 1989-1993 (Box 11)
  - Public Hearings, 1993; Reports, 1980-91, 1980-1993 (Box 12)
  - Assembly papers, 1993; General Correspondence, 1986-94; Asbestos, 1986-93; Capital Newspapers, 1986-90; Training and education programs, 1995-96; Plant Closings, 1987-91; Polygraph/lie detectors, 1987; Pesh: Materials, 1987-90, 1986-1996 (Box 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1983-93; Workers Compensation, 1993; Labor Committee, 1992; Occupational Disease, 1986-90; Clinics, 1989; Labor Correspondence, 1989; OSHA Chemical/workplace, 1986-92, 1983-1993 (Box 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-86; OSHA reform, 1991 Occupational diseases, 1989-96; Worker notification background, 1983-86; Tug Boat strike, 1988 Legal service strike, 1991; Coors boycott, 1989, 1981-1996 (Box 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 16)